B M

BRENDAN MCGINTY

Brendan.mcginty14@gmail.com / C: 757-968-2535 NY, NY 10003

SUMMARY

Brendan is currently a student of UC Berkeley's full-time, full-stack software development bootcamp which will be complete by March 12, 2024. Previously, Brendan was an Operational Risk Executive in Macquarie Asset Management's Public Investments business, with a breadth of risk, advisory, business, and financial experience. Brendan graduated in May 2019 from Wharton's Undergraduate School of Business and has experience leading risk management, consulting, and marketing efforts in large financial and pharmaceutical organizations. His strengths include outstanding leadership skills, quickly developing strong client and team relationships, excellent communication, and driving superior results.

SKILLS (non-technical)

- Financial Risk Management
- Regulatory Affairs
- Project Management
- Risk Analytics
- Client Relationships
- Presentations
- Risk and Controls Self-Assessment
- PowerBI

SKILLS (Technical)

- JavaScript (ES6)
- Github
- REACT
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS / CSS Frameworks)
- HTML
- NoSQL

- Controls Testing
- Issue Management
- Regulatory Remediation
- KRI/KPI Development
- IBM Open Pages
- Microsoft Excel
- PowerPoint
- Assurance
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Application Programming Interfaces (APIs)
- SQL
- Node.js
- Express.js

EXPERIENCE

Operational Risk Executive, Macquarie Asset Management / Macquarie – New York, NY 09/01/2022 – 12/15/2023

Executive within the Mam Public Investments Operational Risk Team providing first line Risk support across the business, including incident and issue management, assurance, framework uplift and development, as well as preparation of board reporting and key strategic analysis for senior management.

- Within 6 months of joining the role, gained deep knowledge of the mutual funds business as well as institutional support and ETF platforms
- Assumed lead role for material issue and incident management / remediation, leading the investigative efforts and subsequent
 project implementation of key issues identified across the business
- Conducted and led several assurance reviews over key trading and valuation processes within the business to identify risks and inefficiencies and implement procedural, policy, or control uplifts
- Aided the Chief Risk Officer in multiple operational and financial analyses of incidents and issues across the business to
 identify thematic trends in financial impact or root cause breakdown, ultimately leading to major initiatives being managed at
 the C-suite level
- Led the effort to redesign Macquarie Asset Management's SOC 1 Report to focus on key risk areas identified during assurance reviews conducted by myself earlier in the year
- Conducted an organizational review of a key team within the business to identify and propose strategic realignment to better fit with the business' objectives
- Worked with the head of Equity trading to redesign the entire global trading model to reduce risk and streamline processes for portfolio managers to focus on research on portfolio management

Senior Analyst, Regulatory Affairs and Aggregate Risk / Macquarie - New York, NY

03/2021 - 08/31/2022

Senior Analyst within the Risk Management Group at Macquarie providing support and financial risk analysis on all North American and European transactions across the entire Macquarie Group.

- Within a year from starting in the role, quickly developed a deep understanding of US / Australian regulations and got up to speed with understanding the full suite of financial products across the Group
- Reviewed over 75 deals for regulatory and financial risk exposure
- Gained experience in presenting complex transactions to executives in Macquarie, honing presentation skills to present complex structures in a professional and clear manner
- Developed an understanding of key International Banking regulations to provide expertise and guidance to all businesses across the Macquarie Group
- Analyzed financial risks associated with transactions across all products within Macquarie's four lines of business, with
 products including securitizations, loan / leasing structures, derivatives, asset management funds, syndication strategies, and
 private equity strategies
- Became a subject matter expert in prudential risk and regulatory capital as required from the Basel Accord following the Global Financial Crisis in 2008
- Developed financial risk models to be used across the Macquarie Group, providing resources to aid the Business in real-time returns projections

Advisory Associate / KPMG - New York, NY

10/2019 - 03/2021

High performing Advisory Associate in KPMG's Capital Markets Risk Management practice supporting a top 5 global Bank. Deep knowledge and expertise with Risk and Control Self Assessments, Controls Testing, Issue Management, and regulatory remediation.

 Worked directly with senior risk Bank executives to develop key strategies for Organizational restructuring across Operational Risk Management

- Led the execution effort for RCSAs across 9 critical IT processes at a global Bank, analyzing each process to identify and
 rate risks, identify, draft, and test key controls to mitigate risks throughout the process, and develop key metrics for identified
 key controls and risks. Planned and led all client meetings and developed strong client relationships
- Aided in remediating an MRA for a bank's Office of Technology and worked with process owners across six of the CoE's IRM
 governance processes to build sustainability packages, track and close out issues, and aided in the development of the final
 materials for the MRA closure package
- Consolidated and analyzed thousands of Issues and Findings into strategic risk initiatives that were approved by senior risk
 executives and implemented across the Bank
- Assisted in the development and review of documentation for Process Flows, Procedures, Control Mapping, Risk and Control Matrices, and Control Testing templates
- Worked on projects to improve critical internal KPMG processes. Maintained status across all workstreams, helped develop key recruitment, retention, and development strategies, and briefed partners bi-weekly on the progress of all internal workstreams across the Service Line
- Assisted in the development of 4 successful business proposals for 4 separate Fortune 500 companies
- Assisted in the research and development of risk management whitepapers for key KPMG clients

Intern, RCC Marketing Team / Pfizer, Inc. - New York, New York May 2018-August 2018

Summer intern for the Pfizer Sutent brand team responsible for leading marketing campaigns, developing marketing strategy, coordinating with advertising agencies and training Pfizer sales associates.

- Marketing lead for several marketing campaigns, including the launch of a new Sutent promotional tabletop campaign for 2018 conferences and Sutent Adverse Reaction Management Guide to educate doctors on managing and monitoring side effects
- Developed marketing strategy working with the Pfizer Sutent brand team
- Coordinated with the ad agency to create the marketing pieces and led the discussion with the internal review committee to gain approval for the marketing pieces
- Created an ad-hoc promotional piece to display for the URO GPO conference
- Worked with ZS Associates to conduct market research and develop strategic insights for the Sutent brand

Intern / Venture Cross Partners, LLC - Great Falls, Virginia

May 2017 - August 2017

Summer intern supporting the managing director to identify potential investments for the firm.

- Conducted industry and data analysis for potential investments across the tech sector, working directly with managing director
- Calculated firm-specific risks and performed DCF calculations associated with respective startup investments

Student Coach / University of Pennsylvania Football - Philadelphia, PA

August 2016 – November 2018

- Medically retired from playing and offered official position on the coaching staff
- In charge of communication between the offensive coordinator and the offense, developing skills in efficient communication

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Wharton School of Business, University of Pennsylvania – Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Bachelor of Science in Economics: Management, Finance

May 2019

University of California, Berkeley Extension - Berkeley, California

March 2024